Wait, wait, did you hear that?
That chant for Palestinian freedom is being criminalized by some European governments.
Police in Austria banned a demonstration because they said the chant is incitement of violence.
The UK's interior minister even said that it's a call for the destruction of Israel.
And in 2018, Mark Lamont Hill was fired by CNN because he dared to say this at the UN.
A free Palestine from the river to the sea.
So what does freedom from the river to the sea actually mean?
And do these people really want to wipe Israelis off the map?
Okay, first, let's break down the chant.
The river they're talking about is this, the River Jordan.
And the sea, that's the Mediterranean.
In between those two bodies of water, 7 million Palestinians live under Israeli rule.
The whole of that land used to be historic Palestine.
And now all of that territory is controlled by Israel.
Actually, we get some unexpected help explaining this from former Israeli Prime Minister Ehud Barak, who said this in 2010.
As long as in this territory west of the Jordan River, there is only one political entity called Israel, it is going to be either non-Jewish or non-democratic.
If this block of millions of Palestinians cannot vote, that will be an apartheid state.
There are around 3 million Palestinians living in the West Bank, and around 2.3 million in the Gaza Strip.
In both of those areas, Palestinians can't vote in the state that rules their lives.
Israel rules over them under a military occupation.
That means the Israeli army controls almost every aspect of their lives, banning them from accessing their land, forcibly evicting them from their homes, telling them when and where they can travel.
Sometimes, they're not even allowed to visit a neighboring town.
And there are around another 1.6 million Palestinians living in what is now Israel.
Although many of them have Israeli passports and they can vote, they don't have equal rights.
Palestinians living in Gaza, the West Bank and Israel all live under a system of apartheid, according to Israeli and international human rights organizations and UN experts.
That means they live under a system that discriminates against them just because they were born Palestinian.
The people forcibly evicted from this land to make way for the state of Israel.
What Ehud Barak was saying was that the Zionist project of a state of Jewish supremacy that rules all of the land between the river and the sea can never be a democracy.
Why?
Because if in the apartheid state that Israel has created, those 7 million Palestinians living under Israeli rule got equal rights and votes, well then Israel's Jewish supremacist system would be democratically ended.
From the river to the sea, Palestine will be free is not an attack on Jews. It's an attack on apartheid.
It's a demand for equality to give Palestinians their basic human rights wherever they live in that chunk of Israeli controlled territory that lies between the river and the sea.
And the sea.
So thank you.
Thank you.
Meaning
And the sea.